Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Papers
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Programs, 1909-1995 (Box 147-152)
  - Programs by performer or subject, 1929-1995
    - Behrend, Siegfried, 1955-1959, 1969-1980, undated (Box-folder 152/5)
    - Centenial concerts, London and Florence, 1995, undated (Box-folder 152/6)
    - Gieseking, Walter, 1954-1956, undated (Box-folder 152/7)
    - Heifetz, Jascha, 1934, 1950-1955, 1970, undated (Box-folder 152/8)
    - Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco performances, 1929-1930, 1939 (Box-folder 152/9)
      Principally with Madeleine Gray
    - Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco performances, 1942-1962 (Box-folder 152/10)
    - Radio performances, 1954-1961, undated (Box-folder 152/11)
    - Tonazzi, Bruno, 1952 (Box-folder 152/12)
    - Transcriptions, 1942-1954, undated (Box-folder 152/13)
- Reviews, 1914-1996 (Box 153-155)
  - Works with opus number, 1915-1996
    - Op. 5: Fuori i barbari (Box-folder 153/1)
    - Op. 7: Coplas (Box-folder 153/2)
    - Op. 17: Cipressi (Box-folder 153/3-4)
    - Op. 18: La sirenetta e il pesce turchino (Box-folder 153/5)
    - Op. 20: La mandragola (Box-folder 153/6-9)
    - Op. 30/1: Alt Wien (Box-folder 154/1)
    - Op. 31: Concerto italiano (Box-folder 154/2)
    - Op. 39: Bacco in Toscana (Box-folder 154/3)
    - Op. 66: I profeti (Box-folder 154/4)
    - Op. 81: Savonarola (Box-folder 154/5)
    - Op. 92: Concerto for piano no. 2 (Box-folder 154/6)
    - Op. 98: Aucassin et Nicolette (Box-folder 154/7-8)
    - Op. 99: Concerto for guitar and orchestra (Box-folder 154/9-10)
    - Op. 104: Stars (Box-folder 154/11)
    - Op. 115: The birthday of the infanta (Box-folder 154/12)
    - Op. 116: Indian songs and dances (Box-folder 155/1)
    - Op. 122: Sacred service for Sabbath eve (Box-folder 155/2)
    - Op. 136: The Octoroon Ball (Box-folder 155/3)
    - Op. 137: Naomi and Ruth (Box-folder 155/4)
    - Op. 143: Guitar quintet (Box-folder 155/5)
    - Op. 146: Concerto da Camera (Box-folder 155/6)
    - Op. 158: Morning in Iowa, Laid in: manuscript copy of poem with annotations (Box-folder 155/7)
    - Op. 161: The Queen of Sheba (Box-folder 155/8)
    - Op. 172: The song of songs (Box-folder 155/9)
    - Op. 186: Vogelweide (Box-folder 155/10)
    - Op. 198: The importance of being ernest (Box-folder 155/11)
  - Other reviews, 1914-1937
    - Kruceniski tour, 1915, Includes reviews of Fuori i barbari (Box-folder 155/12)
    - Miscellaneous reviews, 1914-1926, 1937 (Box-folder 155/13-14)
- Merchant of Venice Materials, 1954-1966 (Box 156)
  - Campari Competition documents, undated (Box-folder 156/1)
  - Clippings, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 156/2-4)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 156/5-9)
  - Libretto, draft, 1954 (Box-folder 156/10)
  - Libretto, printed, undated (Box-folder 156/11)
  - Programs and production materials, 1959-1966, undated (Box-folder 156/12)
- Biographical Materials, 1899-1977 (Box 157-158)
  - Certificates and awards, 1944-1948, undated (Box-folder 157/1)
  - Clippings, 1911-1961, undated (Box-folder 157/2)
  - Date books, address books, passports, 1948-1966, undated (Box-folder 157/3)
  - Description of home and list of possessions, 1945, undated (Box-folder 157/4)
  - Emigration documents and correspondence, 1938-1939, undated, Includes letter to Mussolini (Box-folder 157/5)
  - Expense books, 1944, 1966-1967, undated (Box-folder 157/6)
  - Family estate documents, 1942-1953, undated (Box-folder 157/7)
  - Financial documents, 1939-1941, 1951-1953, 1961-1964, 1977, undated (Box-folder 157/8)
  - Funeral documents, 1968 (Box-folder 157/9)
  - Genealogy documents, 1938 (Box-folder 158/1)
  - Income tax returns, 1940-1954 (Box-folder 158/2)
  - Insurance policies and receipts, 1899-1936, undated (Box-folder 158/3)
  - Letters to government officials, 1938-1942, undated (Box-folder 158/4)
  - List of scores given to Roman Vlad, 1940 (Box-folder 158/5)
  - List of students, 1951-1964, undated (Box-folder 158/6)
  - Marriage certificate [Mario and Clara Castelnuovo-Tedesco], 1929, 1939, 1947, undated (Box-folder 158/7)
  - Military service documents, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 158/8)
  - Music education records and correspondence, 1906-1918 (Box-folder 158/9)
  - Music exam correspondence, 1922 (Box-folder 158/10)
  - Music school and student notebooks, undated (Box-folder 158/11)
  - Naturalization papers, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 158/12)
  - Obituaries, 1968-1974, 1995, undated (Box-folder 158/13)
  - Performance logs, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 158/14)
  - School records, 1906-1918 (Box-folder 158/15)
  - War ration books, undated (Box-folder 158/16)
- Film Music Materials, 1941-1959 (Box 159)
  - The day of the fox [UPA, 1948] (Box-folder 159/1)
  - Desire me [MGM, 1947] (Box-folder 159/2)
  - Etiquette [undated] (Box-folder 159/3)
  - The long wait [Parklane Pictures, 1954] (Box-folder 159/4)
  - The loves of Carmen [Columbia, 1948] (Box-folder 159/5)
  - Miscellany, 1941, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 159/6)
  - Secret command [Torneen, 1944] (Box-folder 159/7)
  - Sergeant Mike [Columbia, 1944] (Box-folder 159/8)
  - Strictly dishonorable [MGM, 1951] (Box-folder 159/9)
  - Time out of mind [Universal, 1947] (Box-folder 159/10)
  - Undercurrent [MGM, 1946] (Box-folder 159/11)
- Bound Materials Owned by Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, 1822-1965
  - Materials annotated by Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, 1822-1957
    - Canti populari toscani, ed. by Giuseppe Tigri. Florence: Barbèra, Bianchi e Co., 1860.
    - Euripides. The Trojan women, transl. by Gilbert Murray. Oxford: Blackwell's, 1925.
    - Hindemith, Paul. Traditional harmony. New York: Associated Music, 1944.
    - Holy Bible. New York: Oxford University Press, undated
    - Jiménez, Juan Ramón. Platero and I, transl. by Eloise Roach. Austin: University of Texas, 1957.
    - Nathan, Robert. Morning in Iowa. New York: A.A. Knopf, 1944.
    - Pentateuch with haftaroth and five megiloth, transl. by Alexander Harkavy. New York: Hebrew Publishing, undated
    - Redi, Francesco. Poesie toscane. Firenze: Leonardo Ciardetti, 1822.
    - Riemann, Ugo. Storia universale della musicirca Torino: Societa Tipografico, 1922.
    - Shakespeare, William. As you like it. New York: Bigelow Smith and Co., 1909.
    - Shakespeare, William. The merchant of Venice, ed. by A. W. Verity. Cambridge: University Press, 1951.
    - Shakespeare, William. The tempest, ed. by M. R. Ridley. New York: E.P. Dutton and Co., 1948.
    - Shakespeare, William. The Winter's tale, ed. by J. H. Lobban. Cambridge: University Press, 1950.
    - Shelley, Percey Bysshe. The Poetical works of Percy Bysshe Shelley, vol. 1. Introduction by A.H. Koszul. New York: E.P. Dutton and Co., 1917.
    - Vogelweide, Walter von der, Gedichte, ed. by Carl von Kraus. Wiesbade: Insel Verlag, 1947.
    - Vogelweide, Walther von der. Walter von der Vogelweide altdeutsch und übertragen von Walther Bulst. Berlin, Leipzig: Tempel Verlag, undated
    - Wilde, Oscar. The plays of Oscar Wilde. Introduction by Edgar Saltus. New York: Modern Library, [circa 1920].
  - Materials inscribed to Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, 1933-1965
    - Moldenhauer, Hans. Duo pianism. Chicago: Musical Press, 1950.
    - Piatigorsky, Gregor. Cellist. New York: Doubleday and Co, 1965.
    - Pirandello, Luigi. Maschere nude. [Italy], 1933.
    - Pizzetti, Ildebrando. Vanna lupa. Pescia: Benedetti, 1949.
    - Toch, Ernst. The shaping forces in music. New York: Criterion, 1948.
    - Vaere, Ulric de. The children of Dom Sierot. Opera libretto, typescript; 11 pp.
  - Scores by other composers, bound for Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, 1909, undated
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van. Sonaten für Pianoforte und Violoncello, ed. by Friedrich Grützmacher; and Sonaten für Pianoforte und Violine, Bound together in one volume entitled "Beethoven Violoncello Sonate"
    - Chopin, Frédéric. Oeuvres complètes. 3 vols. Bote and Bock.
    - Mozart, W. A. La clemenza di Tito, piano score, ed. by Gustav F. Kogel. Leipzig: Peters.
    - Mozart, W. A. Concertos de W. A. Mozart, arr. for piano by Hummel. Henry Litolff's Verlag; and Variationen für Pianoforte solo, ed. by Köhler/Ruthardt. Leipzig: Peters., Bound together in one volume entitled "Mozart concerto variazioni"
    - Mussorgsky, Modest. Boris Godunoff, nuova edizione, riveduta ritoccata e strumentata da N. Rimsky-Korsakoff, transl. by M. Delines et E. Palermi. Piano score. Moscow: Bessel and Co, 1909.
    - Schumann, Robert. Sämtliche Lieder, vol. I ed. by Max Friedlaender and II ed. by Alfred Dörffel, Leipzig: Peters., Bound together in one volume
    - Schumann, Robert. Werke für Pianoforte solo, ed. by Alred Dörffel. 5 vols., Bound together in three volumes